Juncong Lin

Room A516, Administrative Building, Haiyun Campus, Xiamen University, Xiamen, Fujian, P.R.China, 361005 | 86-18859233855 | <u>jclin@xmu.edu.cn</u> | <u>http://gravity.xmu.edu.cn/</u>

Short Biography

Juncong Lin is currently a full professor in the Software School of Xiamen University. He received his B.S. and Ph.D Degree both from Zhejiang University in 2003 and 2008 respectively. Before joining Xiamen University, he has worked in the department of mechanical and automation of Chinese University of Hong Kong as a postdoc researcher (2008.09-2009.03), JST ERATO IGARASHI Design Interface Project as a visiting researcher (2009.05-2009.09), School of Computer Engineering Nanyang Technological University as a postdoc researcher (2009.10-2011.10). His research interests include shape modeling with creativity support, sketch based shape modeling and comic content processing. He has published over 20 papers in venues like ACM SIGCHI, IEEE TVCG. He has been principle investigators of several funding including National Key Technology R&D Program Foundation of China, National Natural Science Foundation of China, Joint Funds of the Ministry of Education of China and China Mobile etc. He has been enrolled in Program for New Century Excellent Talents in University of Fujian (2014), High Level Oversea Talent of Xiamen (2013). He has received several awards including Luzengyong CAD&CG High Tech Award(2012), Xiamen Airline Teaching Award(2015), Excellent Supervisor of Intel Cup National Collegiate Software Innovation Contest(2015), Gold Medal in 2016 China College Student's Entrepreneurship Competition (2016).

Education

- Sep, 2003—Jul, 2008, Zhejiang University, State Key Lab of CAD&CG, College of Computer Science, Ph.D
- Sep, 2000—Jul, 2003, Zhejiang University, Advanced Class of Engineering Education, Chu Kochen Honors College, Minor
- > Sep, 1999—Jul, 2003. Zhejiang University. Environmental Engineering, College of Environmental and Resource Science. B.S

Work Experiences

- ▶ Jul, 2019 present, Professor, School of Informatics, Xiamen University
- Aug, 2017 Jun, 2019, Professor, Software School, Xiamen University
- > Oct, 2011-Jul, 2017, Associate Professor, Software School, Xiamen University
- > Oct, 2009—Oct, 2011, Postdoc Research Fellow, School of Computer Engineering, Nanyang Technological University
- May, 2009—Sep, 2009, Visiting Researcher, IGARASHI Design Interface Project, Japan Science and Technology Agency
- ➤ Sep, 2008—Mar, 2009. Postdoc Researcher, Department of Mechanical and Automation Engineering, The Chinese University of HongKong

May, 2006—Nov, 2006. Research Assistant, Department of Mechanical and Automation Engineering, The Chinese University of HongKong

Fundings

- [3] National Natural Science Foundation of China, 62077039, Research on Holistic Principle based Design Thinking Visualization for 3D Modeling, 2021/01-2024/12, PI
- [3] National Natural Science Foundation of China, 61202142, Research on 3D Modeling with Creativity Support, 2013/01-2015/12, PI
- [4] Joint Funds of the Ministry of Education of China and China Mobile, MCM20130221, Rsearch on Dynamic Image Fast Editing and Realtime Compression for Mobile Internet, 2014/01-2015/12, PI

Publications

- [1] Juncong Lin, Pintong Xiao, Yinan Fu, Yubin Shi, Hongran Wang, Shihui Guo, Ying He, Tong-Yee Lee. C3 Assignment: Camera Cubemap Color Assignment for Creative Interior Design, IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, early access (2020).
- [2] Wei Zeng, Chengqiao Lin, Juncong Lin, Jincheng Jiang, Jiazhi Xia, Cagatay Turkay, Wei Chen. Revisiting the Modifiable Areal Unit Problem in Deep Traffic Prediction with Visual Analytics, IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 27(2):839-848, (2021).
- [3] Xiaoyan Cao, Shihui Guo, Juncong Lin, Wenshu Zhang, Minghong Liao. Online Tracking of Ants Based on Deep Association Metrics: Methods, Dataset and Evaluation, Pattern Recognition, 103:107233 (2020).
- [4] Hechuan Zhang, Zhiyong Chen, Shihui Guo, Juncong Lin, Yating Shi, Xiangyang Liu and Yong Ma. Sensocks: 3D Foot Reconstruction with Soft Stretchable Sensors, Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems CHI '20, accepted.
- [5] Xinyu Shi, Junjun Pan, Zeyong Hu, Juncong Lin, Shihui Guo, Minghong Liao, Ye Pan and Ligang Liu Accurate and Fast Classification of Foot Gestures for Virtual Locomotion. International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality 2019.
- [6] Xing Gao, Guangyu Zhang, Juncong Lin, Minghong Liao: Localized layout analysis for retargeting of heterogeneous images. Multimedia Tools Appl. 77(16): 21163-21184 (2018)
- [7] Haiming Zhao, Chengkuan Hong, Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, Weiwei Xu: Make it swing: Fabricating personalized roly-poly toys. Computer Aided Geometric Design 43: 226-236 (2016)
- [8] Xuekun Guo, Juncong Lin, Kai Xu, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, Xiaogang Jin: CustomCut: On-demand Extraction of Customized 3D Parts with 2D Sketches. Comput. Graph. Forum 35(5): 89-100 (2016)
- [9] Juncong Lin, Jiazhi Xia, Xing Gao, Minghong Liao, Ying He, Xianfeng Gu: Interior structure transfer via harmonic 1-forms. Multimedia Tools Appl. 74(1): 139-158 (2015)
- [10] Juncong Lin, Xing Gao, Minghong Liao, Jiazhi Xia, Guilin Li, Ying He: Making sky lanterns from polygonal meshes. Computers & Electrical Engineering 40(5): 1592-1603 (2014)

- [11] Juncong Lin, Qian Sun, Guilin Li, Ying He: SnapBlocks: a snapping interface for assembling toy blocks with XBOX Kinect. Multimedia Tools Appl. 73(3): 2009-2032 (2014)
- [12] Xuekun Guo, Juncong Lin, Kai Xu, Xiaogang Jin: Creature grammar for creative modeling of 3D monsters. Graphical Models 76(5): 376-389 (2014)
- [13] Qian Sun, Juncong Lin, Chi-Wing Fu, Sawako Kaijima, Ying He: A multi-touch interface for fast architectural sketching and massing. ACM SIGCHI2013: 247-256
- [14] Juncong Lin, Takeo Igarashi, Jun Mitani, and Ying He. "A Sketching interface for sitting pose design in the virtual environment", IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 18(11): 1979-1991 (2012)
- [15] Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, and Charlie C.L. Wang. "Fusion of disconnected mesh components with branching shape", The Visual Computer, Springer, 26(6-8):1017-1025, 2010
- [16] Juncong Lin, Takeo Igarashi, Jun Mitani and Greg Saul. "A sketching interface for sitting-pose design", In Proceedings of the 7th Eurographics Symposium on Sketch-based Interfaces and Modeling, pp111-118, 2010.
- [17] Karl D.D. Willis, Juncong Lin, Jun Mitani, and Takeo Igarashi. "Spatial sketch: bridging between movement & fabrication", In Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Tangible, Embedded and Embodied interaction, pp5-12, 2010
- [18] Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, Charlie C.L. Wang, and Kin-Chuen Hui. "Mesh composition on models with arbitrary boundary topology", IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 14(3):653-665, 2008.
- [19] Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, Zhengwen Fan and Charlie C.L. Wang. "Automatic polycube-maps", In Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Advances in Geometric Modeling and Processing, pp3-16, 2008.
- [20] Xiaogang Jin, Juncong Lin, Charlie CL Wang, Jieqing Feng, and Hanqiu Sun. "Mesh fusion using functional blending on topologically incompatible sections", The Visual Computer, 22(1): 28-42, 2006
- [21] Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, Charlie CL Wang. "Sketch Based Mesh Fusion", In Proceedings of Computer Graphics International, pp 90-101, 2006.
- [22] Juncong Lin, Xiaogang Jin, Charlie CL Wang, Jieqing Feng, Hanqiu Sun, "Topology free mesh fusion", In Proceedings of Pacific Graphics, pp38-40, 2005

Patent

- [1] Xing Gao, Minghong Liao, Yongxuan Lai, Juncong Lin, Lisheng Xiang, A redundancy controlled regtargeting method for comic image, No. 201510022139.0
- [2] Xing Gao, Juncong Lin, Minghong Liao, Guilin Li. A comic image compression method based on explicit hybrid harmonic diffusion. No. 201510750292.5
- [3] Juncong Lin, Xing Gao, Minghong Liao, An snapping method for fast assembly of virtual 3D components, No. 201310126198.3.
- [4] Juncong Lin, Xing Gao, Minghong Liao, A computer aided method for sky lantern making, No. 201310127403.8,

Awards

- [1] Second Prize in 9th China Service Outsourcing Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition, Supervisor, 2018
- [2] Excellent Summer Social Practice Supervisor, 2017
- [3] Excellent Supervisor of Undergraduate Student Academic Competition, 2016
- [4] Golden Prize in China College Student's Entrepreneurship Competition, Supervisor, 2016
- [5] Bronze Prize in 2nd Internet Plus Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition, Supervisor, 2016
- [6] Excellent Summer Social Practice Supervisor, 2016
- [7] Excellent Supervisor of Intel Cup National Collegiate Software Innovation Contest, 2015
- [8] Excellent Summer Social Practice Supervisor, 2015
- [9] Xiamen AirLine Teaching Award, 2015
- [10] New century Excellent Talent of Fujian, 2014
- [11] Second Prize of Xiamen University 8th Youth Teaching Skill Competition, 2013
- [12] High-level Oversea Talent Of Xiamen, 2013
- [13] Luzengyong CAD&CG High-Tech Award, 2012

Professional Services

- [1] China Computer Federation, CAD and Graphics Professional Committee, Member
- [2] China Computer Federation, Virtual Reality and Visualization Technology Professional Committee, Member
- [3] China Computer Federation, Youth Work Committee, Member
- [4] China Society of Image and Graphics, Visualization and Visual Analysis Committee, Member
- [5] China Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics Committee, Member
- [6] Organization Committee of GMP 2017, Member
- [7] Program Committee of ChinaCAD&CG 2018, Member
- [8] Program Committee of ChinaVR 2018, Member
- [9] Program Committee of ChinaVR 2017, Member
- [10] Program Committee of ChinaVR 2016, Member
- [11] Program Committee of HAVE 2014, Member

Referees

Prof Charlie C.L. Wang

Affiliation: Chinese University of Hong Kong

Web: http://www.mae.cuhk.edu.hk/~cwang/

Email: cwang@mae.cuhk.edu.hk

Prof Ying He

Affiliation: Nanyang Technological University

Web: http://www.ntu.edu.sg/home/yhe/

Email: yhe@ntu.edu.sg

Prof Xiaogang Jin

Affiliation: Zhejiang University

Web: http://www.cad.zju.edu.cn/home/jin/

Email: jin@cad.zju.edu.cn